George Constant
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
George Constant papers
1912-2007, bulk 1932-1978
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
George Constant
4.5 linear feet
The papers of modernist painter and printmaker George Constant measure 4.5 linear feet and date from 1912-2007, with the bulk of the material dating from 1932-1978. They consist of biographical material, inventories of artwork, audio interviews and recorded statements on art, personal and business related correspondence, holiday cards, printed material, an exhibition related video recording, and photographs of Constant, his family and friends, and his work.
Provenance
The papers of George Constant were donated by the artist in 1969 and 1978. Additional materials were donated in 2001 and 2007 by his daughter Georgette Preston.
Alternative Forms Available
All of the sound and video recordings in this collection were digitized for research access in 2011 and are available at the Archives of American Art offices. Researchers may view the original cassettes for the archival notations on them, but original cassettes are not available for playback due to fragility.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Biographical Note
Greek American George Zachary Constant (1892-1978) worked from his studios in Shinnecock Hills, and New York City, New York as a painter and printmaker. A founder and lifelong member of the Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors, Constant worked for the Work Projects Administration (WPA) during the Depression and early years of World War II, and exhibited regularly at major galleries and museums from the 1920s to 1970s.
Born in Arahova, Greece, Constant was raised by his two uncles after the death of his parents in 1896. In school and at the monestary one of his uncles led, Constant showed an early interest in classical Greek aesthetics. At the age of eighteen, he immigrated to the United States and continued his art studies at Washington University before transferring to the Art Institute of Chicago. From 1918 to 1922, Constant taught at the Dayton Art Institute and continued to produce and exhibit his work locally. In 1922, he moved to New York, joined the Society of Independent Painters, and became close friends with Society founder and art critic Walter Pach. During the 1920s, his etchings were shown at the Valentine and Downtown Galleries, and at the New Art Circle of J.B. Neumann, where he presented his first one man gallery show in 1929.
From the 1930s to 1940s, Constant produced prints, watercolors, and oil paintings for the WPA, many of which were purchased by museums and public institutions, including the Metropolitan Museum of Art and the Philadelphia Museum. During this same period, Constant exhibited his work at the Boyer Gallery in the late 1930s, and at the Ferargil Gallery from the 1940s to early 1950s. In the decade between 1955 and 1965, Constant also worked on color and set design for seventeen dance productions created by the choreographer Alwin Nikolais. In the last two decades of his career, Constant produced works from his studio in Shinnecock Hills, New York and continued to exhibit at numerous galleries, including Grace Borgenicht Gallery, Guild Hall, Mari Galleries, Tirca Karlis Gallery, and Artium Gallery.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of modernist painter and printmaker George Constant measure 4.5 linear feet and date from 1912-2007, with the bulk of the material dating from 1932-1978. They consist of biographical material, inventories of artwork, audio interviews and recorded statements on art, personal and business related correspondence, holiday cards, printed material, an exhibition related video recording, and photographs of Constant, his family and friends, and his work. A small portion of the correspondence and printed materials are written in Greek.
Biographical material includes artist statements written and recorded by Constant, two audio interview recordings discussing his philosophies on art and his work, inventories of artwork, personal property deeds and legal correspondence, and other miscellaneous material.
Correspondence is predominantly in the form of business and personal letters, postcards, and holiday cards received from family and friends. These include correspondence from Constant's daughter, Georgette Preston, and extended family members. Other frequent personal correspondents include Milton and Sally Avery, Lewis Balamuth, Margaret Brunning, David Burliuk, Nathaniel Burwash, Rhys Caparn, Julia Shaw Patterson Carnell, Phillip Cavanaugh, Morris Davidson, Charles Eaton, Vilko Gecan, Marchal Landgren, Roy Neuberger, Walter Pach, Nell Perret, Constantine Pougialis, Wallace Putnam and Consuelo Kanaga, Hi Simons, and Helen Slosberg. Business related correspondents include Audubon Artists, Art Institute of Chicago, Brooklyn Museum, Carnegie Institute, Dayton Art Institute, Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors, Ferargil Galleries, Guild Hall, Heckscher Museum, Lyman Allyn Museum, Metropolitan Museum, Museum of Modern Art, Spanish Refugee Appeal, and the Whitney Museum. Other business correspondence related to Constant's work with the WPA are also included in the series.
Printed material includes books and booklets on American and Greek art, including a limited print edition of George Constant by George Constant, clippings and articles reviewing Constant's work, exhibition announcements and catalogs of Constant's shows, periodicals profiling his artwork, and dance and theater related programs that Constant consulted on.
Photographs include black and white prints of Constant and his family and friends in St. Louis, Missouri, Dayton, Ohio, and in and around his studio in Shinnecock Hills, New York. The collection also includes photo stills from his 1965 exhibition at the Parrish Art Museum and a comprehensive set of black and white prints, a handful of color prints, and several color slide sheets of Constant's artwork from the 1920s to 1978.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into 4 series:
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1923-2007 (Box 1; 17 folders)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1930-1979 (Box 1-2; 1.4 linear feet)
Series 3: Printed Material, 1927-2005 (Box 2-3; 2 linear feet)
Series 4: Photographic Material, 1912-1978 (Box 4-6; 1 linear foot)
Names and Subject Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects:
Parrish Art Museum
Subjects-Topical:
Art Philosophy; Painters New York (State) New York; Painting, Modern 20th century New York (State) New York; Printmakers New York (State) New York
Types of Materials:
Christmas cards; Interviews; Photographs; Sound recordings; Video recordings
Names:
Avery, Milton, 1885-1965; Avery, Sally; Burliuk, David, 1882-1967; Caparn, Rhys, 1909-; Carnell, Julia Shaw Patterson, 1863-1944; Davidson, Morris, 1898-1979; Gecan, Vilko, 1894-1973; Eaton, Charles Warren, 1857-1937; Kanaga, Consuelo, 1894-; Landgren, Marchal E.; Neuberger, Roy R.; Pach, Walter, 1883-1958; Perret, Nell, 1916-; Preston, Georgette; Putnam, Wallace, 1899-; Art Institute of Chicago; Audubon Artists (New York, N.Y.); Brooklyn Museum; Carnegie Institute; Dayton Art Institute; Ferargil Galleries; Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors; Heckscher Museum; Lyman Allyn Art Museum; Metropolitan Museum of Art (New York, N.Y.); Museum of Modern Art (New York, N.Y.); Spanish Refugee Aid (Organization); United States -- Works Progress Administration; Whitney Museum of American Art
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Biographical Material, 1923-2007, Series 1:
  Biographical material includes artist statements written and read by Constant, two interview sound cassette recordings discussing his philosophies on art and his work, inventories of artwork owned by individuals, museums, and the George Constant Foundation, a notebook inventory of all Constant's oil paintings by rough date, personal property deeds for land owned in Shinnecock Hills and New York City, New York, and New London, Connecticut, and other personal legal documents. This series also includes a certificate of award from the Audubon Artists, Constant's curriculum vitae, three pages from a personal notebook that include a pen and ink sketch, and two passes to WPA buildings.
  - Artist Statements, 1950-1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Certificate of Award, Audubon Artists, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Collectors, George Constant Foundation, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Collectors, Individuals, 1960, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Collectors, Museums, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Family Related Funeral and Will Arrangements, 1926, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Notebook Pages, Sketch and Note on Etchings Sold, circa 1930s (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Notebook, Index to Oil Paintings, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Oral History Interviews, 1978, (transcripts and 3 sound cassettes) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Property, New London, Connecticut, Correspondence, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Property, New London, Connecticut, Land Deeds, 1923-1943 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Property, New York, New York, Deed, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Property, Shinnecock Hills, New York, Appraisal Report, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Property, Shinnecock Hills, New York, Correspondence, 1959-1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Property, Shinnecock Hills, New York, Deeds, 1947-1965 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Property, Shinnecock Hills, New York, General Information, circa 1960s (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Works Project Administration Building Passes, 1939, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, 1930-1979, Series 2:
  Correspondence is predominantly in the form of business and personal letters, postcards, and holiday cards received from family and friends. The Condolences and Family subseries include correspondence from Constant's daughter, Georgette Preston, and extended family members and friends. The General subseries include both personal and business related correspondence. Frequent personal correspondents include Milton and Sally Avery, Lewis Balamuth, Margaret Brunning, David Burliuk, Nathaniel Burwash, Rhys Caparn, Julia Shaw Patterson Carnell, Phillip Cavanaugh, Morris Davidson, Charles Eaton, Vilko Gecan, Marchal Landgren, Roy Neuberger, Walter Pach, Nell Perret, Constantine Pougialis, Wallace Putnam and Consuelo Kanaga, Hi Simons, and Helen Slosberg. Business related correspondents include Audubon Artists, Art Institute of Chicago, Brooklyn Museum, Carnegie Institute, Dayton Art Institute, Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors, Ferargil Galleries, Guild Hall, Heckscher Museum, Lyman Allyn Museum, Metropolitan Museum, Museum of Modern Art, Spanish Refugee Appeal, and the Whitney Museum. The Holiday Cards subseries includes numerous handmade, silkscreened, and printed holiday cards to Constant and his family, with frequent senders including Sally and Milton Avery, Phillip and March Cavanaugh, Morris and Anne Davidson, Dett and Carroll French, Nell and George Perret, and Wallace Putnam and Consuelo Kanaga. The WPA subseries includes business correspondence related to Constant's work with the Project.
  The Correspondence series is arranged into 5 subseries:
  Subseries 2.1: Condolences, 1978
  Subseries 2.2: Family, 1956-1979
  Subseries 2.3: General, 1937-2000
  Subseries 2.4: Holiday Cards, 1954-1978
  Subseries 2.5: WPA, 1934-1968
  - Condolences, 1978, Subseries 2.1:
    - Correspondence, A-E, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, F-N, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, O-Z, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Memorial Guest Book, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Family, 1956-1979, Subseries 2.2:
    - Konstant, Bette, Pam, Paul, and Joan, 1970-1972, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Layne, Maria, and Melina, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - McCarthy, Helen, Dick, and Nikki, 1971, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Millio, Barbara, George, and Christopher, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Preston, Georgette, 1956-1958, 1960, 1963, 1965-1966, 1969, 1973-1974, 1976, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - General, 1937-2000, Subseries 2.3:
    - Addison Gallery of American Art, 1944, 1953, 1955, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Allied Publications, Inc., 1963-1964, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - American Federation of Arts, 1946-1947, 1954-1957, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Archives of American Art, 1969-1971, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Argonaut, 1967, 1969, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Art Institute of Chicago, 1943-1947, 1957, 1961, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Art Students League of New York, 1948, 1957, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Audubon Artists, Inc., 1946, 1955, 1957, 1961-1962, 1966, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - A, Miscellaneous, 1946-1977 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Balamuth, Lewis, 1952, 1969-1970, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Bellevue Gallery, 1974, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Bocour Artists Colors, 1964, 1969, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Breuning, Margaret, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Brooklyn Museum, 1946-1947, 1956, 1960, 1965, 1968, 1970-1971, 1974, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Burliuk, David, 1949-1950, 1956-1957, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Burwash, Nathaniel and Ida, 1966-1967, 191-1972 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Butler Institute of American Art, 1960, 1964, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - B, Miscellaneous, 1955-1978 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Caparn, Rhys, 1957, 1967, 1971, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Carnegie Institute, 1944-1949, 1952, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Carnell, Julia Shaw Patterson, 1930-1939 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - C, Miscellaneous, 1941-1965 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Dayton Art Institute, 1939-1944, 1947, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Dolphin Enterprises (Howland, Jane), 1971, 1973, 1976, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - D, Miscellaneous, 1949-1975 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Eaton, Charles and Isabel, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - E, Miscellaneous, 1939-1990 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors, 1945, 1951, 1965, 1967, 1969-1977 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Ferargil Galleries, 1943-1952 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Ford Foundation, 1958-1960 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - F, Miscellaneous, 1966-1973 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Gecan, Vilko and Auka, 1937, 1947, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - George Baer Gallery, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Grace Borgenicht Gallery, 1951-1956, 1960, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Greek, Miscellaneous, 1949, 1951-1953, 1961-1965, 1969, 1972-1978 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Guild Hall, 1949, 1952, 1957, 1960, 1963, 1965-1972, 1975-1976, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - G, Miscellaneous, 1944-1977 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Heckscher Museum, 1971-1972, 1975, 1977, 1985, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - H, Miscellaneous, 1946-1976 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Isaac Delgado Museum of Art, 1950, 1954, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - I, Miscellaneous, 1948-1978 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Jewish Community Center, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - June 1 Gallery of Fine Art, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - J-K, Miscellaneous, 1942-1978 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Landgren, Marchal E., 1965, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Long Island Arts Center, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - Louis, Marion, 1970, 1973, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - Lyman Allyn Museum, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - L, Miscellaneous, 1951-1978 (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - McClellan, Grace and Grant, 1968, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - Melzer Gallery, 1954, 1956-1959 (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1947, 1950, 1952, 1960, 1972, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - Michigan State University, 1971, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - Museum of Modern Art, 1942-1944, 1950, 1969, 1970, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 81)
    - M, Miscellaneous, 1946-1978 (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - Neuberger, Roy R., 1950, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 83)
    - New School for Social Research, 1948, 1957, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 84)
    - New York WPA Artists Inc., 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 85)
    - N-O, Miscellaneous, 1948-1977 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Pach, Walter, 1942-1945, 1947-1957 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Parrish Art Museum, 1948, 1956, 1963-1964, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, 1948, 1956, 1960-1961, 1963, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Philadelphia Museum of Art, 1960-1961, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Pougialis, Constantine, 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Protestant, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Putnam, Wallace and Kanaga, Consuelo, 1969-1970, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - P, Miscellaneous, 1943-1971 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Renning, Rita and Philip, 1967, 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - R, Miscellaneous, 1932-1976 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Sachs, Hugo L., 1960-1962, 1965-1966, 1968, 1972, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Sights, Sylvia Simons, 1968, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Simons, Hi, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Slosberg, Helen S., 1960, 1962, 1966, 1971, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Solon Society, 1968-1970 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Southampton College Long Island University, 1964, 1967-1971 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Spanish Refugee Appeal (Parker, Dorothy), 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Springs Improvement Society, 1968-1971, 1973, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - S-T, Miscellaneous, 1941-1978 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Ulsher, Sallie, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - University of Kentucky, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - U-V, Miscellaneous, 1947-1975 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Walden School, 1950-1952, 1954, 1956, 1962, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Walker Art Center, 1946, 1949, 1960, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Whitney Museum of Art, 1942, 1952, 1966, 1968, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Wichita State University, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - W-Y, Miscellaneous, 1948-1978 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Zinty, Celestine, 1953, 1958-1960, 1962, 1964, 1968-1970, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Holiday Cards, 1954-1978, Subseries 2.4:
    - Avery, Milton and Sally, circa 1950-1960s (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - B, Miscellaneous, circa 1950-1960s (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Cavanaugh, Phillip and March, 1954-1955, 1957, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Constant, George, circa 1960-1970s (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - C, Miscellaneous, 1963-1965, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Davidson, Morris and Anne, circa 1960s (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - D, Miscellaneous, circa 1950-1960s (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Elstein, Ben, 1957, 1959, 1961, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - E, Miscellaneous, circa 1950-1960s (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - French, Dett and Carroll, 1960-1961, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - F-G, Miscellaneous, circa 1950-1970s (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Greek, Miscellaneous, circa 1950-1970s (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - H-J, Miscellaneous, circa 1950-1970s (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - K-M, Miscellaneous, circa 1950-1960s (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - N-O, Miscellaneous, circa 1950-1960s (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Perret, Nell and George, 1964-1967 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Preston, Georgette and David, circa 1960-1970s (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Putnam, Wallace and Kanaga, Consuelo, circa 1950-1970s (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - P-R, Miscellaneous, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - S, Miscellaneous, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - T-V, Miscellaneous, circa 1950s (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - W, Miscellaneous, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Z, Miscellaneous, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - WPA, 1934-1968, Subseries 2.5:
    - Department of State, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Federal Works Agency, Work Projects Administration, 1940-1942 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - La Guardia, Fiorello, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - O'Connor, Francis V., 1965, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Treasury Department, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - War Department, 1944, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 58)
- Printed Material, 1927-2005, Series 3:
  Printed material includes seven books and nine booklets on American and Greek art, including a limited print edition of George Constant by George Constant, clippings and articles reviewing Constant's work, exhibition announcements, over 150 catalogs of Constant's shows, a videocassette from the 1998 single man show, Exploration of the Universe, three periodical articles profiling his work, and dance and theater related programs that Constant consulted on, a majority of which were choreographed by Alwin Nikolais.
  - Bibliography of Articles on George Constant, 1927-1961, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Book, George Constant by George Constant, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Book, American Art Museum by Walter Pach, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Book, Queer Thing, Painnting by Walter Pach, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Book, Twentieth Century Highlights of American Painting by United States Information Agency, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Books, Greek, Miscellaneous, 1948, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Booklets, 1927, 1947, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Booklets, 1968-1971, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1927-2004, (6 folders) (Box 3, Folder 4-9)
  - Exhibition Announcements, circa 1920s-2000s, (4 folders) (Box 3, Folder 10-13)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1927, 1930, 1935, 1939, (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 14-16)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1940-1944, (5 folders) (Box 3, Folder 17-21)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1945-1949, (5 folders) (Box 3, Folder 22-26)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1950-1951 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1952-1958, 1960-1962, (5 folders) (Box 4, Folder 1-5)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1963-1968, (5 folders) (Box 4, Folder 6-10)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1969-1976, 1978, (5 folders) (Box 4, Folder 11-15)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1983, 1987, 1998, 2005, (catalogs and 1 videocassette) (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, circa 1940-1950s (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Periodicals, 1954, 1977, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Programs and Announcements, Dance and Theater Related, 1955-1965 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Photographic Material, 1912-1978, Series 4:
  Photographs include black and white prints of Constant and his family and friends in St. Louis, Missouri, Dayton, Ohio, and in and around his studio in Shinnecock Hills, New York. The collection also includes three photo stills from his 1965 exhibition at the Parrish Art Museum and a comprehensive set of black and white prints, a handful of color prints, and several color slide sheets of Constant's dry point etchings, oil paintings, watercolors, and other artwork dating from the 1920s to 1978.
  - Photographs of George Constant with Family and Friends, 1912-1969 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Photographs of Exhibition, Parrish Art Museum, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Photographs of Drypoint Etchings, Block Forms, circa 1960-1970s (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Photographs of Drypoint Etchings, Children, circa 1930-1940s (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Photographs of Drypoint Etchings, Landscapes and Still Lifes, circa 1930-1940s (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Photographs of Drypoint Etchings, Portraits, circa 1920-1930s (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Photographs of Lithographs, 1935, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Photographs of Oil Paintings, #1-32 Numbered by Artist, 1932-1974 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Photographs of Oil Paintings, #33-64 Numbered by Artist, 1948-1977 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Photographs of Oil Paintings, Animals, Still Life, Landscapes, 1922-1957 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Photographs of Oil Paintings, Abstract Block Forms, 1956-1975 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Photographs of Oil Paintings, Abstract Human Forms, 1930-1937 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Photographs of Oil Paintings, Abstract Lines, Colors, and Blocks, 1950-1974 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Photographs of Oil Paintings, Block Figures, Couples, 1948-1970 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Photographs of Oil Paintings, Block Figures, Groups, 1948-1963 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Photographs of Oil Paintings, Block Figures, in Space, 1958-1968 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Photographs of Oil Paintings, Block Figures, Vertical, 1947-1958 (Box 5, Folder 9)